# **Bosah Chude**

A data analyst and software developer with experience in developing mathematical models and writing intelligent software solutions. I am well prepared to face the challenges of any rapidly-changing workplace.

No. 49 MCC Road, Owerri, Nigeria. P. O. Box 1700. +234-803-9198-720 bosahchude@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/bosahchude

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Belfox Technologies,** Owerri, Nigeria — *Data Analyst*

DECEMBER 2011 - PRESENT

Collecting, collating, and carrying out complex data analysis to help clients make informed decisions. Also involved in reporting statistical findings to work colleagues and senior managers.

### First Atlantic Semiconductors and Microelectronics, Owerri, Nigeria — App and Embedded Systems Engineer

DECEMBER 2010 - DECEMBER 2011

Job responsibilities included design and development of Android applications, design and maintenance of the Fasmicro Android App Store, oversight of training and seminars on Android technology.

## **FUTO Consult LTD,** Owerri, Nigeria — Windows Software Developer

FEBRUARY 2008 - DECEMBER 2010

Developed various critical data-centric software for use in tracking and reconciling of oil and gas produced within the Niger Delta. These software were developed using mainly Visual Studio, SQL Server and the C Sharp programming language.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Johns Hopkins University,** Baltimore, Maryland — *Data Science Certification*

OCTOBER 2014 - MAY 2015

**Federal University of Technology,** Owerri, Nigeria — B.Eng (Hons) Electrical/Electronics Engineering

SEPTEMBER 2004 - AUGUST 2009

#### **SKILLS**

Database administration
Data gathering and cleaning
Exploratory data analysis
Machine learning
Statistical Inference
Developing data products
Regression analysis
Machine learning
Reproducible research
Python, C#, Java, SQL, R

#### **PROJECTS**

- Developing mathematical models and software for gas aggregation and allocation to downstream sector of the oil economy in Nigeria.
- Developing instruments for the implementation of the domestic gas supply obligation to the downstream sector of the Nigerian economy.
- Developing a data model for onshore and offshore gas royalty reconciliation in the Niger Delta..

#### **LANGUAGES**

English - Very high proficiency in spoken and written from.